Linette Maliakal

http://linmaliakal.com lmaliakal@luc.edu | 847.401.9237

EDUCATION

LOYOLA UNIVERSITY CHICAGO

BS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

May 2020 | Chicago, IL Presidential Scholarship (All Years) Departmental Honors (2020) Dean's List (2016 - 2017) Cum. GPA: 3.70 / 4.0 Major GPA: 3.80 / 4.0

LINKS

GitHub:// linmaliakal LinkedIn:// linette-maliakal Twitter:// @linmaliakal

COURSEWORK

UNDERGRADUATE

Scientific & Technical Communication
Data Structures
Design & Analysis of Computer
Algorithms
Operating Systems
Human Computer Interaction
Software Development: Wireless &
Mobile Devices
Client-Side Web Development
Database Programming
Software Engineering
Natural Language Processing
Objects, Frameworks, and Patterns
(Research Assistant)

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING

Java • JavaScript • HTML5 CSS3 • Python • LATEX C++ • SQL • Assembly Familiar:

iOS • Android • Windows OS MySQL • XAMPP • MongoDB Firebase • IntelliJ • Eclipse Android Studio

DESIGN

InDesign • Canva • Adobe XD Microsoft Office • Prezi

LANGUAGES

Spanish • Malayalam

SUMMARY

Who am I? A geeky software engineer with 3 years of experience coding in Java and 3+ years of experience with UI/UX design and development using HTML5/CSS3 & JS. Asked by founders of Brave Initiatives to speak on behalf of them at their fundraiser.

EXPERIENCE

GIRLS WHO CODE | VOLUNTEER

August 2018 - Present | Chicago, IL

 Aid 20+ girls in developing their website projects, teaching them the meaning of various tag elements and how to design their sites well, assisting them to solve error code in HTML/CSS/JS

LOYOLA IT SERVICES | SERVICE DESK WORKER

July 2019 - May 2020 | Chicago, IL

 Troubleshoot hardware and software related issues, password resets, Remote Desktop issues with MFA and Global Protect set-up, and more for LUC customers

DON'T PANIC! CS | VICE PRESIDENT

August 2018 - May 2020 | Chicago, IL

- Help coordinate meeting times for majority group members to attend, collect information from new members, record notes from meetings
- Develops event and hackathon attendance as group, in charge of communications through email

NORTHWESTERN SMARTCAR HACKATHON | PARTICIPANT

February 2019 | Evanston, IL

 Developed phone application using Cordova framework and Smartcar API as well as various Google APIs for a service to assist roadside car trouble

BRAVE INITIATIVES | Coding Instructor/Coach Intern

May 2018 - September 2018 | Chicago, IL

- Taught coding curriculum for HTML/CSS/JavaScript at Brave Camp, a design thinking & coding camp that empowers high school girls to be agents of change in their local communities.
- Walked the girls through building their own websites with basic web development skills.
- Worked with teams for each week and guided them to think creatively through their ideas and execute them in their sites

PROJECTS

CAMPFIRE | Backend/Frontend Developer

September 2018 - December 2018 | Chicago, IL

Led team and divided tasks to complete for cross-platform mobile application, using the Cordova framework, that connected individuals in the area for event meet-ups. Was awarded the faculty vote and a monetary compensation at Loyola CS Department Semester Celebration.

AWARDS

2020 Grace Murray Hopper Service and Leadership Award
 2018 1st Faculty Vote CS Department Semester Presentations